PERSONAL DETAILS

Address

7 Keepers Mews, Teddington, Middlesex, TW11 9NB. United Kingdom

Contact Telephone

+44 (0) 7802 757277

Email and Website

realcoaching4u@yahoo.co.uk www.realcoaching4u.co.uk

An articulate and highly motivated individual, with twenty years commercial, sales and management experience. Has worked primarily within the Corporate IT sector and possesses a strong blend of skills in people management and business management.

Ronnie is an experienced Coach, with good influencing and communication skills. Ronnie is a passionate and a consistent individual who currently is a Leadership Coach and trainer within IBM UK. Her passion for is to develop Authentic Leadership in corporations with the executives of the future.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

April 2007 — Present day Position Held

IBM UK LTD

Sales Transformation Coach and Leadership Trainer

As part of the Sales Transformation program, I was selected for this role because of my 20 years Sales, Marketing and commercial experience within IBM UK. This combined with my newly acquired Professional Coaching & Leadership qualifications made me the ideal candidate to drive this Organisational change within the Sales Community. The role consists of;

- · Coaching of individuals one to one
- Coaching of individuals and teams with the focus on winning Deals (Deal Coaching)
- Leading Sales Coaching workshops for the Sales Exec, Leaders and Sellers
- Creation and delivery of Leadership Development Programmes
- · Leading Leadership workshops and Leadership Coaching

Jan 2004 - April 2007

IBM UK LTD

Position Held Business Development Executive / Coach in training

Specifically selected to perform the business development role and create the Marketing and Sales strategy for Global Technology Services. The creation of this new Route to Market consisted of;

- The Commissioning and analysis of Market research x-industry for Systems Integrator's to be selected
- The selection and education of new Business Partners
- The Commercial contract negotiation and approvals between IBM and the selected Partners
- Development and implementation of GTS SI Partner Strategy.
- Re-trained as a Certified Professional Co-active Coach (CPCC)

Jan 2003 - October 2003

IBM UK LTD — Sabbatical

During my sabbatical I spent 10 months traveling, including two trips to Australia. I Started my volunteer work on my return.

July 1998 - Dec 2002

IBM UK LTD

Position Held

National Sales Manager – Integrated Technology Services

Holding an executive management position and reporting to the vice president, with six sales managers and 100 sales people reporting to me. The Sales target was achieved, being in excess of 650M USD. My focus in this role was on reorganizing and managing the sales community by line of business and across the industry sectors.

- Manage Sales Managers/Teams Professional Development and Personnel Management
- · Sales Leadership and Sales Community Leadership
- · Weekly and Quarterly Sales Forecasting
- Weekly tracking of Top opportunities
- Run Selection Clinics for Sales Teams and Client Managers

Spent 12 months as a Client Services Principal in Financial Services before going on sabbatical

July 1988 - July 1998

IBM UK LTD

Positions Held

Technical, Sales, Management, Regional Marketing Manager

I joined IBM in Manchester as a Customer Services Representative, where I looked after a number of customers from a Software Engineering perspective. I was their first point of contact when they had software problems on their computers. I very quickly moved from this into delivery of services, for a fee to customers on their sites. Again very quickly I moved into sales and made a very good living selling services into the industry even before IBM has established its Global Services Business around the world. I spent a number of years managing a profit and loss and also during this time trained for my Chartered Institute of Marketing Qualification.

July 1978 - July 1988

Sharp Electronics UK LTD

I worked for Sharp Electronics UK where I worked from leaving school. I started there as a Computer Operator and left as their Technical support manager. This was a great training ground for my future career in IBM. As a young woman in the late 1970's I learned to cope with a male dominated culture and worked out how to 'achieve' in this environment – that experience has 'served me well' over the years.

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

September 1973 - June 1978

St. Damians RC Secondary School - Manchester

5 O Level's 6 GCSE's

Vocational Training

Personal Trainer and Aerobics instructor

Mentor training with Trailblazers Charity at Feltham YOI

Youth worker with 'the youth café'

Mentor in the community

Other

CTI Co-active Coaching Certification (CPCC)

CTI Leadership Program Graduate

Accredited Certified Coach (ACC)

CTI Co-active Coaching Fundamentals training CTI Co-active Coaching Intermediate training

CRR ORSC Fundamentals training

CRR ORSC Intermediate Training - Nov 07-Mar 08

TCI Team Diagnostics Intensive

IBM Global Sales School

IBM LDC (Leadership Development Centre) Assessor

IBM Advanced Personal Development

IBM Advanced Coaching skills for Leaders

IBM Coaching for Leaders, and Coaching skills 1,2 and 3. IBM Exec resources training - Unleashing potential 1 & 2

Chartered Institute of Marketing Advanced training

INTERESTS & BACKGROUND

I have retrained as a co-active coach and I truly believe that I was born to do this work. I have transformed my life by using co-active coaching techniques and my desire is to help others to do the same.

I have worked for many charities including 'Trailblazers' the charity that works at Feltham Young Offenders Institute, to help young offenders to 'go straight'. Also I have worked by the Youth Café project which is a youth club for youngsters between the ages of 14-18. I am currently about to embark on mentoring in the community to befriend a young person and guide them through life's every day issues. I get lots of satisfaction and learning from my volunteer work.

I love to workout and stay healthy and do so three or four times a week. I love to walk and cycle. I am also a qualified personal trainer and aerobics instructor. I also have a passion for people and love to travel, Sydney Australia is my favourite city!

OTHER INFORMATION

Date of Birth -

23rd August 1962

Marital Status -

Single

Driving Licence -

Full UK, current and clean

Referees -

Details available on request